<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--Arbortext, Inc., 1988-2013, v.4002-->
<!DOCTYPE body SYSTEM ".\DTD\USMCV1-V1_modified_xml.dtd" [
<!ENTITY ESD_basic_symbol SYSTEM "GRAPHICS/ESD_basic_symbol.jpg" NDATA jpg>
]>
<?Domainfile href='.\PSM130.lst'?>
<?TOCfile href='.\PSM130.toc'?>
<?Stylesheet href='.\styles\content1.STY'?>
<?Title href="TM 12541A-OD/1 AN/PSM-130 APPLICATION PROGRAM SET MANUAL"?>
<body>
<?FRAME id='C2s1a' title='CHAPTER 2 - SAFETY PRECAUTIONS' previous='.\C1s1.xml!C1s2N'?>
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="1" TEXT="CHAPTER 2 - SAFETY PRECAUTIONS"?>
<chapter id="chapter2" label="CHAPTER 2" tocentry="1">
<title>SAFETY PRECAUTIONS</title>
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="2" TEXT="Section I. Introduction."?>
<section id="c2s1" label="Section I. Introduction.">
<para0 id="p2-1" label="2-1" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="3" TEXT="2-1 Introduction."?>
<title>Introduction.</title>
<?ALERT id="w212" type="warning"?>
<para><emphasis emph="b">Warning</emphasis> statements highlight an
essential operating or maintenance procedure, practice, condition,
statement, etc., which if not strictly observed, could result in injury
or death of personnel.</para>
<?ENDALERT?>
<?ALERT id="c212" type="caution"?>
<para><emphasis emph="b">Caution</emphasis> statements highlight an
essential operating or maintenance procedure, practice, condition,
statement, etc., which, if not strictly observed, could result in
damage or destruction of equipment.</para>
<?ENDALERT?>
<para>This chapter contains information on safety precautions for
the APS. Section I contains general information on Safety Responsibilities
and Notifications. Section II contains a General Safety Summary. Section
III contains Maintenance Safety Precautions.</para>
<para>Personnel who use or perform maintenance on the APS must be
familiar with the contents of this document. Safety considerations
fall into two categories: personnel safety and equipment safety. Basic
safety requirements and concepts are discussed in System Safety Program
Requirements, MIL-STD-882E. Specific precautions, based on design
features of the APS, are presented in the paragraphs below.</para>
<subpara1 id="p2-1.1" label="2-1.1" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-1.1 Safety Responsibilities."?>
<title>Safety Responsibilities.</title>
<para>Ultimately, individuals are responsible for their own safety,
the safety of others working on or near the system, and the safe operation
of the equipment. The processes and procedures described in this manual
require compliance with standard safety precautions. The technician
must adhere to the procedures, recommendations, warnings, and cautions
provided to ensure the safe use, handling, storage, and disposal of
components. This section provides general safety precautions and instructions
that must be applied during maintenance of the APS to ensure personal
safety and health and the protection of Government property. (Portions
of this chapter are repeated elsewhere in this manual for reinforcement.)</para>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-1.2" label="2-1.2" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-1.2 Safety Notations - Warnings, Cautions And Notes."?>
<title>Safety Notations - Warnings, Cautions And Notes.</title>
<para>Warning, Caution, and Note statements have been strategically
placed throughout the text. These statements are considered essential
to the protection of personnel or equipment and property and are placed
prior to the procedures to which they apply. A warning or caution
applies each time the related step is repeated. Before starting any
task, review the warnings, cautions, or notes included in the text
for that task. Warning, Caution, and Note statements are set apart
from standard text content (as illustrated below) and immediately
precede the paragraphs or steps to which they apply.</para>
</subpara1>
<para><warning id="w212">
<para><emphasis emph="b">Warning</emphasis> statements highlight an
essential operating or maintenance procedure, practice, condition,
statement, etc., which if not strictly observed, could result in injury
or death of personnel. 		</para>
</warning> </para>
<para><caution id="c212">
<para><emphasis emph="b">Caution</emphasis> statements highlight an
essential operating or maintenance procedure, practice, condition,
statement, etc., which, if not strictly observed, could result in
damage or destruction of equipment.</para>
</caution></para>
<para> <note>
<para><emphasis emph="b">Note</emphasis> statements highlight an essential
operating or maintenance procedure, condition, or statement.</para>
</note> </para>
</para0>
</section>
<?FRAME id='C2s2b' title='CHAPTER 2 - SAFETY PRECAUTIONS'?>
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="2" TEXT="Section II. General Safety Summary."?>
<section id="c2s2" label="Section II." tocentry="1">
<title>General Safety Summary.</title>
<para0 id="p2-2" label="2-2" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="3" TEXT="2-2 Introduction."?>
<title>Introduction.</title>
<para>The following paragraphs will provide a general safety summary
for this APS.</para>
<subpara1 id="p2-2.1" label="2-2.1" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-2.1 Electrical Current."?>
<title>Electrical Current.</title>
<para>Electrical current sufficient to cause death or injury to personnel
is present throughout the equipment used for maintenance of the APS.
All personnel must be aware of the measures required to prevent and
treat electrocution.</para>
<subpara2 id="p2-2.1.1" label="2-2.1.1" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="5" TEXT="2-2.1.1 Emergency Procedures For Victims Of Electrical Shock."?>
<title>Emergency Procedures For Victims Of Electrical Shock.</title>
<para>If someone becomes the victim of electrical shock, perform the
following step-by-step procedures:</para>
<step1 label="Step 1. ">
<para>Do not try to pull or grab the individual.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="Step 2. ">
<para>Turn off electrical power. If electrical power cannot be turned
off, use a wooden pole, a rope, or some other insulating material
to pull, push, or lift the person to safety.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="Step 3. ">
<para>Send for help as soon as possible.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="Step 4. ">
<para>After injured person is free of contact with the source of electrical
shock, move the person a short distance away and check breathing and
pulse.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="Step 5. ">
<para>If the person has stopped breathing, immediately start artificial
resuscitation. If the person does not have a pulse, immediately start
Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation.</para>
</step1>
</subpara2>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-2.2" label="2-2.2" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-2.2 ESD Hazards And Precautions."?>
<title>ESD Hazards And Precautions.</title>
<para>Equipment that uses electronic components can experience problems
ranging from occasional breakdowns and degraded performance to complete
failure. A major cause of these problems can be traced to Electrostatic
Discharge. Electrostatic Discharge is the release of static electricity
caused by the rapid transfer of static electrical charge between bodies
of different electrical potential. Ensure that proper precautions
are taken whenever and wherever sensitive devices are to be handled.</para>
<subpara2 id="p2-2.2.1" label="2-2.2.1" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="5" TEXT="2-2.2.1 ESD Awareness, Management And Symbol."?>
<title>ESD Awareness, Management And Symbol.</title>
<para>All maintenance actions described in this manual could result
in damage to parts. All sensitive parts must be handled in accordance
with management procedures described in TM 9999-15/1, Electrostatic
Discharge Awareness, and TM 9999-15/2, Electrostatic Discharge Management.</para>
<para>All sensitive components should display the ESD symbol. Select
"<?hotspot display="50%" linktype="picture" href="./graphics/Fig2-1_1.pic"?>Figure
2-1. Basic ESD Symbol.<?endhotspot?>" to view the symbol used to identify
all components that can be effected by electrostatic discharge.</para>
</subpara2>
<subpara2 id="p2-2.2.2" label="2-2.2.2" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="5" TEXT="2-2.2.2 ESD Damage Prevention."?>
<title>ESD Damage Prevention.</title>
<para>When handling sensitive equipment or parts, perform the following
steps to prevent damage:</para>
<step1 label="Step 1.">
<para>Attach personnel ground strap to wrist and chassis ground prior
to removing sensitive equipment.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="Step 2.">
<para>Store circuit cards in approved protective packaging immediately
upon removal from the equipment.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="Step 3.">
<para>Use an ESD workstation for troubleshooting any item.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="Step 4.">
<para>Inspect the protective packaging of all replacement items for
indications of damage to packaging during shipment.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="Step 5.">
<para>Ground the package prior to the removal of the item.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="Step 6.">
<para>Install replacement items immediately upon removal from protective
packaging.</para>
</step1>
</subpara2>
</subpara1>
</para0>
</section>
<?FRAME id='C2s3c' title='CHAPTER 2 - SAFETY PRECAUTIONS' next='.\C3s1.xml!C3S1a'?>
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="2" TEXT="Section III. Maintenance Safety Guidelines."?>
<section id="c2s3" label="Section III." tocentry="1">
<title>Maintenance Safety Guidelines.</title>
<para0 id="p2-3" label="2-3" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="3" TEXT="2-3 Introduction."?>
<title>Introduction.</title>
<para>The following section provides a summary of the operational
maintenance safety for the APS.</para>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.1" label="2-3.1" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.1 General Maintenance Safety Guidelines."?>
<title>General Maintenance Safety Guidelines.</title>
<para>The following paragraphs provide general maintenance safety
guidelines:</para>
<step1 label="(a)">
<para>Allow only qualified maintenance personnel to perform corrective
maintenance actions on electronic equipment and components.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="(b)">
<para>During corrective maintenance or repairs on electronic equipment
or components, under no circumstances should any person service or
adjust the equipment except in the presence of someone who is capable
of rendering aid.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="(c)">
<para>Ensure that all internal and external grounds are properly connected
before energizing shop equipment.</para>
</step1>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.2" label="2-3.2" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.2 Personal Maintenance Safety Guidelines."?>
<title>Personal Maintenance Safety Guidelines.</title>
<para>The following paragraphs provide personal safety guidelines:</para>
<step1 label="(a)">
<para>Do not wear loose or floppy clothing, rings, wrist watches,
and/or any other conductive material.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="(b)">
<para>Keep all metal objects clear of any energized device.</para>
</step1>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.3" label="2-3.3" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.3 Hand Tool And Test Equipment Maintenance Safety Guidelines."?>
<title>Hand Tool And Test Equipment Maintenance Safety Guidelines.</title>
<para>The following paragraphs describe the APS hand tool and test
equipment maintenance safety guidelines:</para>
<step1 label="(a)">
<para>Use tools with insulated handles, grips, or bodies when working
on electronic equipment.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="(b)">
<para>Use only AC grounding type (3-prong) tools, test equipment,
or extension power cords.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="(c)">
<para>Discharge all capacitors before taking any measurements on any
de-energized equipment.</para>
</step1>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.4" label="2-3.4" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.4 Handling Chemical Agent Safety Guidelines."?>
<title>Handling Chemical Agent Safety Guidelines.</title>
<para>The following paragraphs provide chemical agent safety guidelines:</para>
<step1 label="(a)">
<para>Ensure working area is adequately ventilated when using chemicals.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="(b)">
<para>Use the correct type of chemical for the correct application
on a specific equipment.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="(c)">
<para>Use only approved chemical agents or materials. Do not use unauthorized
chemical agents or materials to clean or repair equipment items.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="(d)">
<para>Do not use flammable solvents, such as gasoline, benzene, ether,
or like substances, as cleaning solvents for electronic parts or components.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="(e)">
<para>Do not use carbon tetrachloride as a cleaning solvent.</para>
</step1>
<step1 label="(f)">
<para>When using cleaning solvents or chemical washes, allow the equipment
to cool before applying the solvent. Never apply a cleaning solvent
to internal parts of energized equipment.</para>
</step1>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.5" label="2-3.5" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.5 Do Not Service Alone."?>
<title>Do Not Service Alone.</title>
<para>Do not attempt internal service or adjustment unless another
person capable of rendering aid and resuscitation is present.</para>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.6" label="2-3.6" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.6 Keep Away From Live Circuits."?>
<title>Keep Away From Live Circuits.</title>
<para>Operating personnel must at all times observe safety regulations.
Do not replace components inside the equipment with the voltage supply
turned on. Under certain conditions, dangerous potentials may exist
when the power control is in the off position due to charges retained
by capacitors. To avoid injuries, always remove power from, discharge,
and ground a circuit before touching it. Adhere to all lock out/tag
out requirements.</para>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.7" label="2-3.7" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.7 Resuscitation."?>
<title>Resuscitation.</title>
<para>Personnel working with or near high voltages or hazardous materials
shall be trained in modern methods of resuscitation.</para>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.8" label="2-3.8" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.8 Flammable Liquids."?>
<title>Flammable Liquids.</title>
<para>When flammable liquids are used in compartments containing non-operating
equipment, be sure that there is sufficient ventilation to avoid any
accumulation of fumes and that all fumes are cleared before the equipment
is energized. When flammable cleaners and primers are being applied,
approved explosion-proof lights, blowers, and other equipment shall
be used. Ensure that firefighting equipment is readily available and
in working order.</para>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.9" label="2-3.9" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.9 Chemicals/Cleaners."?>
<title>Chemicals/Cleaners.</title>
<para>Keep in approved safety containers and in minimum quantities.
Some cleaners/chemicals may have an effect on skin, eyes, and respiratory
tract. Observe manufacturer WARNING labels, Safety Data Sheets (SDS),
and current safety directives for proper handling and disposal of
cleaners/chemicals and soiled clothing. Use only in authorized areas.
Unless otherwise indicated in the text, use as described in this publication
should not result in any immediate health concerns. Consult the local
Bio-environmental Engineer for specific protective equipment and ventilation
requirements.</para>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.10" label="2-3.10" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.10 Personal Protective Equipment."?>
<title>Personal Protective Equipment.</title>
<para>Wear protective clothing/equipment (gloves, apron, eye protection,
etc.) approved for the materials and tools being used. Contact supervisor
for guidance. If necessary, the local Bio-environmental Engineer should
be contacted for guidance.</para>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.11" label="2-3.11" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.11 Soldering."?>
<title>Soldering.</title>
<para>Personnel shall use eye protection when soldering. Soldering
irons are hot; use proper precautions to prevent burns. Avoid fumes
generated by soldering. Good general ventilation is normally adequate.</para>
</subpara1>
<subpara1 id="p2-3.12" label="2-3.12" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="2-3.12 Do Not Wear Jewelry."?>
<title>Do Not Wear Jewelry.</title>
<para>Remove rings, watches, and other metallic objects which may
cause shock or burn hazards. Snagged finger rings have caused many
serious injuries. Remove finger rings during all periods of maintenance.</para>
</subpara1>
</para0>
</section><?Pub Caret -2?>
</chapter>
</body>
