<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--Arbortext, Inc., 1988-2013, v.4002-->
<!DOCTYPE body SYSTEM ".\DTD\USMCV1-V1_modified_xml.dtd">
<?Pub Inc?>
<?Domainfile href='.\PSM130.lst'?>
<?TOCfile href='.\PSM130.toc'?>
<?Stylesheet href='.\styles\content1.STY'?>
<?Title href="TM 12541A-OD/1 AN/PSM-130 APPLICATION PROGRAM SET MANUAL"?>
<body>
<?BUTTON POS='1' LABEL='Comp Lay' TYPE='pic' LINK='./graphics/Fig3-26_1.pic' bitmap='n' DESC='Open Component Layout.'?>
<?BUTTON POS='2' LABEL='UUT Sch' TYPE='pic' LINK='.\graphics\Fig3-27_1.pic' bitmap='n' DESC='Open UUT Schematics.'?>
<?BUTTON POS='3' LABEL='ID Sch' TYPE='pic' LINK='./graphics/Fig3-32_1.pic' bitmap='n' DESC='Open ID Schematics.'?>
<?BUTTON POS='4' LABEL='TPS' TYPE='program' LINK='C:\USR\TYX\BIN\WRTS.EXE "PSM130\Gun Turret Drive Assy\GTD_Pwr_Supply _(7566131-121)\TP_LAV_GTD_PSU.OBJ"' bitmap='n' DESC='Select to launch GTD Power Supply TPS.'?>
<?FRAME id='C3s10a' title='CHAPTER 3 - THEORY OF OPERATION.' next='.\C3s10.xml!C3S10b' previous='.\C3s9.xml!C3S9b'?>
<chapter>
<section id="c3s10" label="Section X." tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="2" TEXT="Section X. GTD Power Supply."?>
<title>GTD Power Supply.</title>
<para0 id="p3-10" label="3-10" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="3" TEXT="3-10 Introduction."?>
<title>Introduction.</title>
<para>The following paragraphs provide information on the Theory of
Operation for the GTD Power Supply. Part information is also provided
in paragraph <?hotspot href="p3-10.2"?>3-10.2 Part Information<?endhotspot?>.</para>
<subpara1 id="p3-10.1" label="3-10.1" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="3-10.1 Theory Of Operation."?>
<title>Theory Of Operation.</title>
<para>The GTD Power Supply contains two major functions: (1) a DC
Power Supply (DCPS) and (2) an 800 Hz AC source generator for Turret
positioning resolution. The DC/DC converter is a Switched Mode Power
Supply that provides split rail +/- 15 VDC. This provides bias supply
for many of the on-board control circuits (op amps), 800 Hz base transistor
drive circuitry and some off-board devices. The 800 Hz Power Supply
generates a 26 V sine wave oscillating at 800 Hz. This sine wave is
distributed off-board to the shaft resolver armature coils for resolver
turret angle calculations. The Power Supply incorporates fault protection
and shutdown devices for over voltage and over current conditions. </para>
<subpara2 id="p3-10.1.1" label="3-10.1.1" numbering="1" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="5" TEXT="3-10.1.1 GTD Power Supply Equipment Description."?>
<title>GTD Power Supply Equipment Description.</title>
<para>The GTD Power Supply is a circuit card that measures 11-11/16&rdquo;
x 8-9/16&rdquo;. It includes 3 transformers, one 40 pin connector,
20 gold fingers, 3 power transistors mounted on a heatsink bar, and
a number of resistors, capacitors, and DIP ICs.</para>
</subpara2>
<subpara2 id="p3-10.1.2" label="3-10.1.2" numbering="1" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="5" TEXT="3-10.1.2 DCPS Description."?>
<title>DCPS Description.</title>
<para>Referring to schematic <?hotspot display="50%" linktype="picture" href="./graphics/Fig3-27_1.pic"?>Figure
3-27. GTD Power Supply Schematic<?endhotspot?>, 28 volts nominal DC
is supplied via J1 to pins J1-5 and J1-4 for DCPS and AC 800Hz power
supply input source voltage. CR18 and CR17 provide blocking diode
protection on the input side. L1, C21, and C22 are input filtering
to reduce input power supply noise. CR19 and CR20 provide a path for
current to flow during input disconnection. A control circuit for
the DC/DC converter is centered around U8 (SG1525AJ) which provides
the PWM control necessary to maintain proper regulation of the DCPS.
Two bias paths for the control circuit (one through R44, CR21) and
a feedback path through CR22 maintain bias on U8. The main switching
transistor is Q6 (2N6756) and is driven by U8 pin 11. The Power Train
for the DCPS is a fly back configuration and energy is stored in transformer/inductor
T3. R57 and R56 are two redundant shunt paths that provide a monitor
of the current passing through Q6. In the event of an overload condition,
Q7 will turn on and provide a shutdown signal to U8 through CR26 and
connection to pin 8 of U8. C25 and R48 set the switching frequency
for U8 which is approximately 80kHz. VR4, 5, and 6 provide over voltage
protection for the control circuit. C27 and R52 are snubber components
which protect Q6 during switching. R45 and R46 set the feedback voltage
ratio for use by U8 to achieve the appropriate regulation set point.
The switched waveform is passed through T3 and CR23 and CR24 provide
the current path to support the + and &ndash; 15 volt output voltage
rails. C28, 29, 32-25 and L2 provide all necessary output stage filtering
for the +/- 15 VDC outputs. </para>
</subpara2>
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="5" TEXT="3-10.1.3 800Hz AC Supply."?>
<subpara2 id="p3-10.1.3" label="3-10.1.3">
<title>800Hz AC Supply.</title>
<para>The 800 Hz AC supply is a sinusoidal reference supply. The 800
Hz source has three main functional sections: (1) 800 Hz output drive
created by Q1, Q2, Q3 and Q4 along with surrounding components T1,
diodes, T2 (output transformer) and associated output filter C10,
(2) Oscillator reference voltage provided by U1, U2 and surrounding
passives (R&rsquo;s and C&rsquo;s) and (3) Reference Voltage control
and feedback and over voltage and over current shutdown circuits established
via U3 &ndash; U7 and Q5.</para>
<para>Q3 and Q4 control the main drive through +28 volts bias supplied
via center tap of E2 connection at Transformer 2. The main reference
source for the 800 Hz signal is created via a controlled Wein Bridge
oscillator configuration at U1. Sinusoidal voltage at the output of
U1 is passed through U2 which provides amplification and feedback
control of the AC output through resistor network R8, R10-12 and C8.
The sinusoidal reference signal is supplied to the base connections
of Q1 and Q2 which provide a push/pull base drive through T1 to Q3
and Q4. </para>
<para>Feedback and control of the 800Hz AC output is provided via
AC voltage feedback at R22 and R23. VR1 and VR2 offer protection against
voltage surges. Two feedback paths exist to provide control; the first
path was described in the previous paragraph and exists via connection
through U2 and is described as a &ldquo;fast&rdquo; feedback path.
The second path is via a &ldquo;longer term&rdquo; rms to DC converter
which is created via U6. Feedback signal presented at R32 is full
wave rectified via the configuration around U6 including CR13 and
CR14. The Full wave rectified output of the AC source is filtered
via U7 and associated feedback network and provides a negative voltage
to the gate of the depletion mode FET (Q5). As the impedance of Q5
increases (driven further into depletion due to higher output voltage),
the output voltage of U1 pin 10 will decrease as well in correspondence
and reduce the output voltage. As the output voltage decreases below
an acceptable point, the RMS to DC converter (U6) will decrease and
in doing so will increase the gate drive to Q5 thereby reducing its
impedance and raising the level of the 800Hz reference U1. The Gate
of Q5 will sit at about -2 volts during steady state conditions.</para>
<para>Protection against over voltage on 28 volts input which could
cause damage and excessive voltage is provided by U5 using sense resistors
R28 and R29 as monitor divider points. If >37 volts is supplied via
J1-4 input, U5 pin 5 threshold will exceed pin 4 which is held at
&ndash; 5.0 volts via reference VR3 and will cause the output of U5
to go high through CR16 and drive the output of U7 to the low rail
cutting off the depletion mode FET Q5 and shutting down the AC output.</para>
<para>Protection against over current on Q3 and Q4 is provided via
sensing the voltage across shunt R21. U3 will switch when the voltage
at pin 4 is > pin 5 (diode drop via CR11). At approximately 3.5 amperes
through the path from either Q3 or Q4 to ground, U3 will pulse low
and fire the monostable configuration (555) U4. Output of U4 will
go high for several seconds shutting down the AC output via path through
CR15 and U7 again causing Q5 to cut off and shut down oscillator U1.</para>
<para>Monitor points are provided throughout the AC 800 Hz source
for verifying the operation of the many control, protection, and reference
signals.</para>
</subpara2>
</subpara1>
<?FRAME label='C3s10b' title='CHAP. 3 - THEORY OF OPERATION,  SECT. X - GTD Power Supply' image=".\graphics\Fig3-25_1.pic" next='.\C3s11.xml!C3S11A' previous='.\C3s10.xml!C3S10a'?>
<subpara1 id="p3-10.2" label="3-10.2" tocentry="1">
<?PUB TOCLEVEL="4" TEXT="3-10.2 Part Information."?>
<title>Part Information.</title>
<para>The following provides part information for the GTD Power Supply.</para>
<para>Refer to <?hotspot href="T3-9"?>Table 3-9<?endhotspot?> for
part information.</para>
<para><table id="T3-9">
<title id="T3-9">Table 3-9. GTD Power Supply Part Information</title>
<tgroup align="left" cols="5">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.50*"/>
<colspec colname="COL2" colwidth="0.60*"/>
<colspec colname="COL3" colwidth="0.49*"/>
<colspec colname="col4" colwidth="1.39*"/>
<colspec colname="col5" colwidth="0.43*"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry align="center">Fig. 3-25 and Index Number</entry>
<entry align="center">Part Number</entry>
<entry align="center">CAGEC</entry>
<entry align="center">Description</entry>
<entry align="center">Quantity (Qty)</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry align="center">1</entry>
<entry align="center">7566131-121</entry>
<entry align="center">13160</entry>
<entry>Circuit Card Assembly, GTD Power Supply</entry>
<entry align="center">1</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table> </para>
</subpara1>
</para0>
</section>
</chapter>
</body><?Pub Caret 3?>
